# **Mellania Permata Sylvie**

Balongbendo, Sidoarjo, East Java

085781761657 | mellaniapermata@gmail.com | in Mellania Sylvie | nellasylvie

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Bachelor of Information Systems from Trunojoyo Madura University with GPA 3.79. Have big passion in programming and data science. Advance in operating computer and proficient using Microsoft Office applications. Proven strong communication skill, management skill, public relations through organizational and commitee experiences. Highly motivated to learn more, develop my skills and grow professionally.



#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Dicoding Indonesia** 

External Code Reviewer

June 2022 - Current

Bandung (remote) | Freelance

- Successfully reviewed over 2500+ machine learning and front-end web project assignments submitted by students. I have received a rating of 4.9/5.0 from the students.
- Provide feedback and share valuable tips on writing good programming code.
- Actively engage in answering students' questions and providing solutions through the discussion forum to facilitate student's learning process

## Komisi Pemilihan Umum Kab. Sidoarjo

**February 2023 – March 2023** 

Petugas Pantarlih

Sidoarjo | Contract

- Conducted voter registration for the 2024 general election in Indonesia. successfully completed the data collection activities before the deadline
- Reported the results of the voter registry (matching and research) on the report forms and recorded them in the E-Coklit application

## Badan Pusat Statistik Kab. Sidoarjo

October 2022 - November 2022

Petugas Pendata Lapangan

Sidoarjo | Contract

- Conducted data collection on the social, economic, and educational conditions of residents as part of the REGSOSEK (Social and Economic Registration) activity.
- Coordinated with Field Supervisors (PML), Village Heads, and Neighborhood Association (RT) Leaders to carry out the data collection process.
- Compiled and reported the data collection results on the report forms and uploaded the report on the Wilkerstart Regsosek and Regsosek Khusus applications.

## **Bangkit Academy**

February 2022 - July 2022

Machine Learning Facilitator

Jakarta (remote) | Part Time

- Led and guided 23 participants through the Machine Learning training program. 20 out of 23 students successfully graduated from the Bangkit Academy program.
- Supervised the participants' learning progress through reports on Google Spreadsheet and reviewed their daily reports on the Kampus Merdeka website.
- Provided consultation sessions with the participants and scheduled them using Google Calendar.
- Served as an assistant instructor during the classes and coordinated through email.

## **EDUCATION**

## University of Trunojoyo Madura

**August 2018 – February 2023** 

S.Kom, Information Systems (GPA: 3.79/4.00)

Bangkalan

Undergraduate Thesis: "Breast Cancer Classification Through Ultrasonography Images Using Modified Convolutional Neural Network ResNet152v2"

- 3rd best graduate of Information Systems major.
- Actively participate in english community and being semifinalist of National University Debating Competition (NUDC) Trunojoyo University 2021.

SMA Negeri 1 Tarik Science major (MIPA) July 2015 - June 2018

Sidoarjo

- Being a school representative to joined National Physic Olimpic in 2016.
  - Actively participate in scientific papers community and responsible to tending the school's garden.

#### **SKILLS**

Tech Skills: Programming (Python, JavaScript, Java), SQL, Power BI, Tensorflow, System Design, HTML/CSS, Git,

Microsoft Office, Google Workspace, Windows, Troubleshoot.

Softskills: Communication, strategic planning, administrative management, adaptability, critical thinking

Languages: Indonesian (native), English (intermediate)

## **PROFESSIONAL TRAINING**

Data Engineer May 2022 – June 2022

Fresh Graduate Academy DTS Kominfo

Jakarta (online)

- Learned with DQLab platform about basic skill of being data engineer, such as python programming, fundamental SQL, data cleaning and manipulation with pandas.
- Worked on simple ETL (Extract, Transform, Load) project with pandas.

## Pengembang Machine Learning & Front-End Web

**August 2021 – January 2022** 

Dicoding Indonesia

Bandung (online)

- Learned about machine learning, deep learning, and front-end web material in Dicoding platform.
- Worked on capstone project with team (2 person) to build program with machine learning & front-end solution.

Machine Learning February 2021 – July 2021

Bangkit Academy

Jakarta (online)

- Learned with Coursera platform to built machine learning models until deployment using multiple frameworks.
  - Work with team in making Capstone Project, collecting data, cleaning, preprocessing, building, and evaluate models, deploy it become E-RCV mobile apps with Capstone's team (6 people).

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

| • | Tensorflow Developer Certificate   Tensorflow                  | September 2021 |
|---|--|----------------|
| • | Google IT Automation with Python Specialization   Coursera     | March 2021     |
| • | Google IT Support Specialization   Coursera                    | March 2021     |
| • | DeepLearning.Al Tensorflow Developer Specialization   Coursera | April 2021     |
| • | Data Engineer   Digital Talent Scholarship                     | August 2022    |

Google Data Analytics Certificate | Coursera

February 2023

#### **ORGANIZATION EXPERIENCE**

# Google Developer Student Club Trunojoyo Madura

Bangkalan

Core Team

August 2021 – July 2022

- Responsible for conducting research and developing the potential abilities of GDSC members.
- Participating in organizing activities that enhance skills such as webinars, study groups, training, and competition preparations

## **Engineering English Community Trunojoyo Madura**

Bangkalan

Secretary

January 2020 – December 2020

- Managing all administrative activities of the organization, such as letter drafting, recording and tracking incoming and outgoing correspondence.
- Compiling activity proposals, funding proposals, partnership proposals, and activity accountability reports.
- Scheduling and announcing meeting agendas with the executives or members, and serving as the secretary during meetings.
- Maintaining and organizing the organization's document archives.

## Member of Debate Division

August 2018 - December 2019

- Organizing study sessions to enhance members' communication and argumentation skills.
- Conducting research on the agenda of English debate competitions.
- Providing training sessions on English debate in preparation for competitions.
- Represented the faculty to take part in the English debate competition